Tufts-New England Medical Center Records MS224
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts-New England Medical Center Records
1960 -- 1980
1929 -- 1990
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Boston Dispensary
Tufts-New England Medical Center
Boston Floating Hospital
Pratt Clinic/New England Center Hospital
School of Medicine
Tufts Medical Center
MS224
58.8 Linear Feet 49 record boxes
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 5 series: Legacy collection documentation; Administration records; Cancer Center; Financial records; and Planning office records.
Custodial History
This collection was originally part of the archives of the New England Medical Center (NEMC), which closed in 1990. The collection was processed by Dave Nathan, archivist at the NEMC archives, in July 1989, and had the following NEMC acquisition numbers: 84-28, 85-12, 85-17, 85-35, 85-1, 85-37, 87-3, 86-54, 83-2, 83-9, 83-13, 84-2, 84-18, 84-27, 84-29, 85-12, 86-37, 86-25.
In spring 2013, NEMC material was transferred from NEMC to a restoration company for conservation treatment, and was then transferred to off-site storage in custody of Digital Collections and Archives (DCA). In December 2014 and January 2015, the material was transferred to DCA for processing. Some material originally in the NEMC archives was not transferred to DCA, due to either poor condition or loss.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains reports, architectural and engineering plans, surveys, correspondence, financial records, and grant documents by and about the Tufts-New England Medical Center and Tufts-New England Medical Center, Inc. The files in this collection primarily deal with parking, properties management, urban planning in the South Cove neighborhood of Boston, and research grant projects undertaken at the hospital. Of particular note are the Administrative records series, which offers a periodic overview of division and department operations, and the Planning records series, which documents the physical expansion of the hospital, as well as the proposed integration between the hospital and Tufts University. The physical collection documentation folder of this collection includes copies of Dave Nathan's original finding aid entries as well as copies of the original acquisition records.
As there was a periodic shifting of departments to and from NEMC/T-NEMC and their constituent institutions, any comprehensive search of a particular topic over time must involve also consulting the other NEMC archives collections at DCA. Contact DCA for more information about associated materials.
This collection suffered extensive water damage due to a flood before it was in the custody of DCA. It underwent conservation efforts before processing, but several materials, particularly folders, scrapbooks, and bound volumes, are still warped or retain a musty odor. In addition, some items are fragile, and must be handled carefully
Related Materials
MS099, New England Medical Center records, DCA
Dave Nathan transferred images to the Visual Materials collection at the New England Medical Center archives in 1989 -- and T-NEMC photographs are now located in the Photographs and audiovisual materials series of the New England Medical Center records (MS099.001). Other T-NEMC records may also be found in MS099, as noted above.
MS213, Boston Floating Hospital records, DCA
MS214, Boston Dispensary records, DCA
MS222, Pratt Clinic/New England Center Hospital records, DCA
MS228, Bingham Associates Fund records, DCA
Biographical / Historical
The Tufts-New England Medical Center (T-NEMC) was the official partnership between Tufts University and the New England Medical Center. In 1930, the School of Medicine, the Boston Dispensary, and the Boston Floating Hospital for Infants and Children created an alliance known as the New England Medical Center. Over the next forty years the evolution of NEMC, the physical move of the Medical and Dental Schools to Chinatown, and the overall shift in health care necessitated the need for a joint venture between Tufts and NEMC, a unified organization which would provide medical care as well as support research and teaching. Now named the Tufts Medical Center, it is the primary teaching hospital for Tufts Schools of Medicine and Dental Medicine, and is located in the Chinatown neighborhood of Boston.
In 1930, the governing bodies of the Boston Dispensary (BD), the Boston Floating Hospital for Infants and Children (BFH), and the Trustees of Tufts College created the New England Medical Center (NEMC). NEMC was established as a non-profit organization to coordinate the operations of its constituent organizations. Population growth and newer approaches to providing citizens economical medical care would foster the evolution of NEMC over the next two decades. In 1938, for instance, a donation from William Bingham, 2nd built the Joseph H. Pratt Diagnostic Hospital. Over time, the Pratt Clinic expanded, and subsumed the BD. The need for additional space dictated the addition of Farnsworth Surgical Building and Ziskind Research Center. The merging of these hospital units became the third piece of NEMC, the New England Medical Center Hospital (NEMCH). NEMCH was a 452-bed non-profit hospital that addressed needs in cardiology, cancer, endocrinology, hematology, kidney disease, among others. At NEMCH, patient care was integrated with student and physician training, as well as research, further cementing the relationship between NEMC and Tufts.
A physical move of the Schools of Medicine and Dental Medicine to Harrison Avenue in Chinatown, the same neighborhood as the hospitals, provided access for students and physicians. Yet, despite these physical advancements, an organizational structure unifying these entities was still lacking. Each unit operated under its own governing body, which made decision making across the medical center cumbersome. To address this issue, an organized planning effort began for NEMC to become one fully integrated, multi-operational complex dedicated to research, teaching, and medical care.
In 1965, the University/Hospital alliance was named the Tufts-New England Medical Center. It included the three units of NEMC and Tufts University Schools of Medicine and Dental Medicine. In addition, a separate corporation was established to jointly govern the University and Hospital, known as T-NEMC, Inc., incorporated in 1968. T-NEMC, Inc. had its own board, composed of members of the Board of Trustees of Tufts, as well as members of the Board of Governors of NEMC. This collaboration would continue to grow, with professors at the School of Medicine advocating for T-NEMC to serve as the primary teaching hospitals for the School of Medicine.
By 1976, T-NEMC controlled common services, which included health care studies, medical engineering, community health and ambulatory care, employee-student health services, communications, parking facilities, property ownership, and public relations. By the late 1970s both institutions had experienced a change in leadership, and interest in collaboration dissipated.
Tufts and NEMC, once again separate after T-NEMC, Inc. was dismantled, drafted a new affiliation agreement in 1991. In 2000, the center was once again named Tufts-New England Medical Center, and in 2008 was renamed the Tufts Medical Center, reflecting the working partnership between Tufts University and the New England Medical Center hospitals.
Tufts-New England Medical Center; New England Medical Center; Tufts Medical Center; Tufts College. Medical School; Tufts University. School of Medicine; Boston Dispensary; Boston Floating Hospital; Pratt Diagnostic Clinic; New England Medical Center Hospital; Primary medical care; Hospitals--Medical staff; Ehrlich, Edward; Medical care; University history; Medicine -- History; Medical history
- Legacy collection documentation, 1990; MS224.001; 1.2 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the finding aids by NEMC archivist Dave Nathan, as well as NEMC acquisition records.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Legacy collection documentation folder, 1990; MS224.001.001.00001 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
- Administration records, 1929 -- 1985; 1970 -- 1980; MS224.002; 20.4 Linear Feet
  This series primarily contains correspondence and administrative files of Edward Ehrlich, Executive Assistant of T-NEMC, on a variety of topics, and are arranged by subject. The material is a periodic overview of division and department operations. Several folders relate to the medical center's physical expansion, such as reports from outside agencies, constructions plans, and maps. This series also includes financial information, such as budgets, expense reports, and purchase orders, as well as some publicity materials, such as brochures.
  Consult the Administration records series in the New England Medical Center records (MS099.003) in addition to this series for a holistic view of the organization over time.
  Folders containing financial and personnel information are restricted.
  75 years from the date of creation. Open for research.
  - AIS, 1975 -- 1977; MS224.002.001.00002 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1975; MS224.002.001.00003 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Annual report, 1976; MS224.002.001.00004 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Annual report to the president, 1969; MS224.002.001.00005 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Applicants, 1976; MS224.002.001.00006 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - A.P.A. members, MS224.002.001.00007 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Service award recipients, 1975; MS224.002.001.00008 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Alcohol Detoxification Unit, 1973 -- 1976; MS224.002.001.00009 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Ambulatory-Community Health, 1971 -- 1976; MS224.002.001.00010 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Ameiican Management Association, 1969 -- 1975; MS224.002.001.00011 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Amerioan College Health Association, 1975; MS224.002.001.00012 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Annual Meeting - Association of American Medical Colleges, 1973; MS224.002.001.00013 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Areawide Health Construstion Planning, 1971; MS224.002.001.00014 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Art Work - New Building, 1973; MS224.002.001.00015 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Empl oyee Badging Group, 1976; MS224.002.001.00016 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Beal and Company (taxes), 1974; MS224.002.001.00017 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Blue Cross - Blue Shield, 1973 -- 1976; MS224.002.001.00018 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Boston City Directory, 1971 -- 1972; MS224.002.001.00019 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Boston transportation planning review, 1972; MS224.002.001.00020 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Boston Bicentennial, 1972 -- 1973; MS224.002.001.00021 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Boston University Students, 1975; MS224.002.001.00022 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Boston Waterfront Facility, 1973; MS224.002.001.00023 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - B.R.A. - Combat Zone, 1974; MS224.002.001.00024 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - B.R.A. - Music Hall, 1974; MS224.002.001.00025 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - B.R.A. - Rent Payments, 1971; MS224.002.001.00026 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - B.R.A. - Cutback, 1970; MS224.002.001.00027 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - B.R.A. - Leased Property, 1970 -- 1971; MS224.002.001.00028 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Traffic Direction, 1972 -- 1973; MS224.002.001.00029 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Boston Neighborhood Health Advisory Council, 1971; MS224.002.001.00030 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Calisti, Louis, 1971 -- 1972; MS224.002.001.00031 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Carl Martin Pharmacy, 1967 -- 1972; MS224.002.001.00032 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - C.B.I., 1971 -- 1972; MS224.002.001.00033 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Chelsea Old Soldiers Home, 1977; MS224.002.001.00034 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Child care, 1974 -- 1975; MS224.002.001.00035 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Code 99 Task Force, 1974; MS224.002.001.00036 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Cohen, Perry, MS224.002.001.00037 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Church of all Nations, 1976; MS224.002.001.00038 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Contributions, 1967 -- 1975; MS224.002.001.00039 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Cost Containment, 1977; MS224.002.001.00040 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Cresap, McCormack-Paget, Inc., 1975; MS224.002.001.00041 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Donations, 1969 -- 1974; MS224.002.001.00042 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Hospital Disaster Plan, 1973; MS224.002.001.00043 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Development of Associated Health Education Organization grant application, 1976; MS224.002.001.00044 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - NEMCH Development Fund, 1975; MS224.002.001.00045 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Dept. of Health and Hospitals, City of Boston, 1971; MS224.002.001.00046 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Bosco, Don, 1971 -- 1973; MS224.002.001.00047 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Dorchester Health Care, 1971; MS224.002.001.00048 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Edison Easement Agreement, 1972; MS224.002.001.00049 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Educational Assistance Program, 1976; MS224.002.001.00050 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Educational Media Center, 1970; MS224.002.001.00051 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - V.A. Hospital, 1970 -- 1971; MS224.002.001.00052 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Equipment, 1971 -- 1973; MS224.002.001.00053 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Employee Recognition Day, 1973 -- 1974; MS224.002.001.00054 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Envelope Inserting Machine, 1971; MS224.002.001.00055 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Environmental Impact Study, 1975; MS224.002.001.00056 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Environmental Protection Agency, 1974 -- 1975; MS224.002.001.00057 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Executive Council, 1972 -- 1976; MS224.002.001.00058 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Freeze - wage and price, 1975; MS224.002.001.00059 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Fellowships, 1975; MS224.002.001.00060 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - First National Bank of Boston, 1976; MS224.002.001.00061 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Foundations, 1972; MS224.002.001.00062 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Arthur Vining Davis Foundation, 1970; MS224.002.001.00063 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Pratt, Laurence, 1970 -- 1971; MS224.002.001.00064 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Gifts, 1972 -- 1974; MS224.002.001.00065 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Governor's Task Force on Transportation, 1970; MS224.002.001.00066 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Grants, 1970; MS224.002.001.00067 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Hartford Street Presbyterian Church, 1970 -- 1971; MS224.002.001.00068 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Harvard University, 1969; MS224.002.001.00069 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Health Care Convocation, 1972; MS224.002.001.00070 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Health Care Feasibility Study, 1974; MS224.002.001.00071 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Health Facilities Laboratories, 1970 -- 1971; MS224.002.001.00072 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Health Manpower Development Program, 1971 -- 1972; MS224.002.001.00073 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Health Information Specialists, 1972; MS224.002.001.00074 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Health Planning Council for Greater Boston, 1970 -- 1971; MS224.002.001.00075 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Health Service-Mental Health Administration, 1971; MS224.002.001.00076 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Heliport, 1974; MS224.002.001.00077 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Herald Traveler Supplement, 1972; MS224.002.001.00078 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Hill, Larry, 1976; MS224.002.001.00079 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Hospital Job Training, 1973; MS224.002.001.00080 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Boston Institutional Study, 1970; MS224.002.001.00081 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Jacobs, Helen, 1975; MS224.002.001.00082 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Jacobs, Arthur, 1974 -- 1977; MS224.002.001.00083 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - T-NEMC Job Study, 1967 -- 1968; MS224.002.001.00084 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Joint Planning Committee, 1969 -- 1970; MS224.002.001.00085 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Joint Review Group, 1976; MS224.002.001.00086 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Krant, Melvin, 1974; MS224.002.001.00087 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Learning Resource Committee Minutes, 1970 -- 1976; MS224.002.001.00088 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Library, 1975; MS224.002.001.00089 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Licensing Board, 1975; MS224.002.001.00090 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Life Insurance- T-NEMC, 1973; MS224.002.001.00091 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Long-range Planning Committee, 1976; MS224.002.001.00092 (Box MS224 Shared 1)
  - Maloney, William, 1974; MS224.002.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Malpractice Insurance, 1976; MS224.002.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Management Control Committee, 1973 -- 1974; MS224.002.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Management in Practice, 1975; MS224.002.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Massachusetts Association for the Blind, 1974 -- 1977; MS224.002.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Massachusetts Department Against Discrimination, 1975; MS224.002.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Massachusetts Health Council, 1969 -- 1972; MS224.002.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Massachusetts Nurses Association, 1970 -- 1974; MS224.002.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Massachusetts Public Health, 1971; MS224.002.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Mayor's office B.R.A., 1970 -- 1975; MS224.002.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - MBTA, 1975; MS224.002.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - Medical electronics, 1974 -- 1976; MS224.002.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - Medical Staff By-Laws, 1953 -- 1974; MS224.002.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - Memorandums, 1970 -- 1974; MS224.002.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - MHEFA, 1971; MS224.002.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - Motivational dynamics, 1975 -- 1976; MS224.002.002.00016 (Box 2)
  - Moving, 1976; MS224.002.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - MUMPS Design Review Group, 1976; MS224.002.002.00018 (Box 2)
  - Murname Progress Report, 1977; MS224.002.002.00019 (Box 2)
  - Music Hall, 1975; MS224.002.002.00020 (Box 2)
  - National Center for Health Service Research and Development, 1971; MS224.002.002.00021 (Box 2)
  - Nationwide Conference Education Center, Inc., 1972; MS224.002.002.00022 (Box 2)
  - NEMCH room rates, 1976; MS224.002.002.00023 (Box 2)
  - Organzation Structure, MS224.002.002.00024 (Box 2)
  - O.S.H.A., 1973; MS224.002.002.00025 (Box 2)
  - Osborne, Maurice, 1971; MS224.002.002.00026 (Box 2)
  - Park Plaza Development, 1975; MS224.002.002.00027 (Box 2)
  - Posner Area, 1969; MS224.002.002.00028 (Box 2)
  - International Municipal Parking Congress, 1972 -- 1974; MS224.002.002.00029 (Box 2)
  - Pediatric Bill of Rights, 1973; MS224.002.002.00030 (Box 2)
  - Public Meeting, 1975; MS224.002.002.00031 (Box 2)
  - Purchasing, 1975; MS224.002.002.00032 (Box 2)
  - T-NEMC Purchasing Proposal, 1970; MS224.002.002.00033 (Box 2)
  - Completed Purchase Orders, 1976 -- 1977; MS224.002.002.00034 (Box 2)
  - Rehabilitation Engineering, 1977; MS224.002.002.00035 (Box 2)
  - Research Overhead Submission, 1977; MS224.002.002.00036 (Box 2)
  - S. D. L., 1974; MS224.002.002.00037 (Box 2)
  - Search Committee, 1974 -- 1975; MS224.002.002.00038 (Box 2)
  - Society for Advancement of Management, 1973 -- 1975; MS224.002.002.00039 (Box 2)
  - St. Elizabeth's Hospital, 1972 -- 1977; MS224.002.002.00040 (Box 2)
  - Sheldon-Roberts study, 1971 -- 1972; MS224.002.002.00041 (Box 2)
  - Security - Farnsworth, 1976; MS224.002.002.00042 (Box 2)
  - Security - Pratt, Harvard St., 1976; MS224.002.002.00043 (Box 2)
  - Security - Proger, 1976; MS224.002.002.00044 (Box 2)
  - Security - Ziskind, 1976 -- 1977; MS224.002.002.00045 (Box 2)
  - Security - C & E, 1975; MS224.002.002.00046 (Box 2)
  - Security - Equipment, 1975 -- 1977; MS224.002.002.00047 (Box 2)
  - Security - Fire Prevention, 1975 -- 1977; MS224.002.002.00048 (Box 2)
  - Security - Hospital Burglary Fund, 1977; MS224.002.002.00049 (Box 2)
  - Security - Insurance, MS224.002.002.00050 (Box 2)
  - Security - ID Badge Program, 1976 -- 1977; MS224.002.002.00051 (Box 2)
  - Security - Incident Reports, 1976 -- 1977; MS224.002.002.00052 (Box 2)
  - Slattery Brothers, 1970; MS224.002.002.00053 (Box 2)
  - Student Health Service, 1974 -- 1976; MS224.002.002.00054 (Box 2)
  - Committee to Evaluate Veterinary Service Functions, 1975; MS224.002.002.00055 (Box 2)
  - Veterans Administration Hospital, 1970 -- 1976; MS224.002.002.00056 (Box 2)
  - Western Reserve Associates, 1975; MS224.002.002.00057 (Box 2)
  - Xerox, 1974; MS224.002.002.00058 (Box 2)
  - Zoning, 1977; MS224.002.002.00059 (Box 2)
  - Ziskind Research Fund, 1977; MS224.002.002.00060 (Box 2)
  - Union 1199, 1973; MS224.002.002.00061 (Box 2)
  - Union Hospital Contract, 1974; MS224.002.002.00062 (Box 2)
  - Urban Renewal, 1971; MS224.002.002.00063 (Box 2)
  - Vacations, 1974 -- 1975; MS224.002.002.00064 (Box 2)
  - T-NEMC History, 1976; MS224.002.002.00065 (Box 2)
  - T-NEMC Radiology Associates, 1974 -- 1976; MS224.002.002.00066 (Box 2)
  - Transfer to T-NEMC Personnel, 1975; MS224.002.002.00067 (Box 2)
  - Tufts Asian Cultural Center, 1974; MS224.002.002.00068 (Box 2)
  - Tufts Council of Associated Hospitals, 1976; MS224.002.002.00069 (Box 2)
  - Tufts Medical Alumni Day, 1974; MS224.002.002.00070 (Box 2)
  - Tufts Medical Center Associates, 1975; MS224.002.002.00071 (Box 2)
  - Tufts University, 1977; MS224.002.002.00072 (Box 2)
  - Fringe Benefits - Tufts University, 1976; MS224.002.002.00073 (Box 2)
  - Tufts - Financial Office Meeting, MS224.002.002.00074 (Box 2)
  - Torrens, Paul, 1972; MS224.002.002.00075 (Box 2)
  - Temporary Fund - Cost Sharing, 1975; MS224.002.002.00076 (Box 2)
  - Temporary Fund - Grants, MS224.002.002.00077 (Box 2)
  - TMCA, 1974 -- 1977; MS224.002.002.00078 (Box 2)
  - T-NEMC Fall Assembly, 1973; MS224.002.002.00079 (Box 2)
  - Transformer Cooling, 1974; MS224.002.002.00080 (Box 2)
  - T-NEMC: Fringe Benefits, 1969 -- 1971; MS224.002.002.00081 (Box 2)
  - Student insurance, 1974 -- 1980; MS224.002.002.00082 (Box 2)
  - Ehrlich, Edward, 1973 -- 1977; MS224.002.002.00083 (Box 2)
  - Plan B.R.A. Master Plan, 1972 -- 1974; MS224.002.002.00084 (Box 2)
  - Bradford Hotel, 1977 -- 1979; MS224.002.002.00085 (Box 2)
  - Plan B.R.A. Utility Meeting, 1972 -- 1975; MS224.002.002.00086 (Box 2)
  - Wheel Chair Ramp, 1975; MS224.002.002.00087 (Box 2)
  - Building Code, 1977; MS224.002.002.00088 (Box 2)
  - Bradford, 1977; MS224.002.002.00089 (Box 2)
  - PROP. 193H. General, 1976 -- 1977; MS224.002.002.00090 (Box 2)
  - PROP. 193H. Construction Est., 1977; MS224.002.002.00091 (Box 2)
  - Plan Dental Building, 1970; MS224.002.002.00092 (Box 2)
  - Plan Murname, 1977 -- 1978; MS224.002.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - PROP. MBTA Pre-1973 File, 1972 -- 1973; MS224.002.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - PROP. 201H. Tenants/Utilities, 1978; MS224.002.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - PROP. 193H. Contracts and Agreements, 1977 -- 1978; MS224.002.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - PROP. 193H. Plans and Programs, 1977; MS224.002.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - PROP. 193H. Construction Bills, 1977; MS224.002.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - PROP. Hadge R/M, 1974 -- 1977; MS224.002.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Birth Defects Center, 1977 -- 1978; MS224.002.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Educational Media Center, 1976 -- 1978; MS224.002.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - 203 Harrison Ave - Evictions, 1978; MS224.002.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Learning Resources Committee, 1978; MS224.002.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - PROP. 193H. Hadge Financial, Budget, 1976 -- 1980; MS224.002.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - PROP. Tenant problems, 1974 -- 1978; MS224.002.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - PROP. 193H. Former tenents, etc., 1977 -- 1978; MS224.002.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - Employee student health service, 1972 -- 1974; MS224.002.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - Quimby (1 of 2), 1975 -- 1978; MS224.002.003.00016 (Box 3)
  - Quimby (2 of 2), 1978 -- 1979; MS224.002.003.00017 (Box 3)
  - T-NEMC veterinary service, 1975 -- 1977; MS224.002.003.00018 (Box 3)
  - L.A.M. Space Backlog, 1979; MS224.002.003.00019 (Box 3)
  - L.A.M. Report, 1979; MS224.002.003.00020 (Box 3)
  - System Monthly Report, 1975 -- 1977; MS224.002.003.00021 (Box 3)
  - Budget Sheets, 1977 -- 1980; MS224.002.003.00022 (Box 3)
  - McNally, Joan, 1977; MS224.002.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - PKG Design Standards, 1975; MS224.002.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Educational Media Center - Budget, 1972 -- 1973; MS224.002.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Directorship, 1977; MS224.002.004.00004 (Box 4)